The 'Maggie' is a comedy film directed by Alexander Mackendrick.
The poor, elderly—and the wily, when it comes to parting those who can afford it from their money—Scottish skipper of a
broken-down old 'puffer' boat tricks an American tycoon into paying him to transport his personal cargo.
When the tycoon learns of the trick, he attempts to track
down the boat and remove his possessions.
Calvin B. Marshall, the American, played by Paul Douglas.
Captain McTaggart, the Skipper, played by Alex Mackenzie.
The Mate, played by James Copeland.
The Engineer, played by Abe Barker.
Doogie, the Wee Boy, played by Tommy Kearins.
Pusey, played by Hubert Gregg.
Hobson's Choice is a 1954 British romantic comedy film directed by David Lean.
It is based on the 1916 play of the same name by Harold Brighouse.
It stars Charles Laughton in the role of Victorian bootmaker Henry Hobson, John Mills as  timid but highly
talented employee Will Mossop, and Brenda de Banzie as Hobson's eldest, fiercely determined daughter.
The film also features Prunella Scales in one of her first cinematic roles.
Hobson's Choice won the British Academy Film Award for Best British Film 1954.
The film explores themes of ship, scotland, glasgow, scotland, boat, skipper.
The tone is lighthearted.